Lincoln Filene Center Records UA018
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Lincoln Filene Center Records
1944 -- 1998
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Lincoln Filene Center (1961-1999)
Center for Civic Education
Civic Education Foundation
Tisch College
Lincoln Filene Center (2002- )
University College
Hollister, Robert M.
UA018
67.7 Linear Feet 95 boxes
57 Volumes
10 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized in three series: Subject files; Publications; and Unprocessed accessions.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains brochures, budgets, correspondence, grant proposals, minutes, newsletters, programs, publications, and reports pertaining to the Lincoln Filene Center from 1944-1998. Significant people in this collection include Robert Hollister, the former director of the Lincoln Filene Center.
Some material was pulled by Russell Miller in preparation for his history of Tufts University, Light on the Hill.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Biographical / Historical
The Lincoln Filene Center for Citizenship and Public Affairs was originally the Living Flame Memorial Foundation, founded in 1945 to provide civic education in the aftermath of World War II. In 1951 the Foundation changed its name to the Civic Education Foundation. Tufts University President Nils Yngve Wessell expressed an interest in the Foundation, and in 1954, the Civic Education Foundation began operating from Tuft's campus, where it became the "Tufts College Center for Civic Education in cooperation with the Civic Education Foundation." In 1955, the Lincoln and Therese Filene Foundation endowed the Lincoln Filene Professorship in Citizenship and Public Affairs, and in 1961 the center became known as the Lincoln Filene Center for Citizenship and Public Affairs. In 1989, the Center merged with Tufts University and was no longer a separate entity. The Board of the Civic Education Foundation became the Board of the Lincoln Filene Center. The Center conducted workshops for teachers at disadvantaged schools, worked to improve the Boston area school system, held the annual Massachusetts Assemblies on State Government from 1959 to 1968, and conducted Black Awareness programs for Tufts staff members in the 1960s and 1970s. The Lincoln Filene Center was also responsible for publications on various topics related to citizenship, government, and public affairs. Broadly, the mission of the Lincoln Filene Center was to promote active citizen participation and the study of the components of citizen participation. In 2002, the Lincoln Filene Center became a division of the Tufts University College of Citizenship and Public Service. This College became the Jonathan M. Tisch College of Citizenship and Public Service in 2006.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Academic Centers and Institutes; Student activism
- Subject files, 1944 -- 1997; 1950 -- 1997; UA018.001; 32.25 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains material collected by Russell Miller in preparation for his history of Tufts University, Light on the Hill. This material was organized by subject and no attempt has been made to recreate the original order of the material.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Miscellany, 1950 -- 1997; UA018.001.001
    - Press Releases, Announcements, 1950 -- 1997; UA018.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    - Press Releases, Publications, 1950 -- 1997; UA018.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
      This folder contains press releases and correspondence pertaining to the Lincoln and Therese Filene Foundation grant that supported the construction of the Lincoln Filene Center.
    - N.E. Environmental Grant, 1950 -- 1997; UA018.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
    - Massachusetts Association of Conservation Commissions, 1950 -- 1997; UA018.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence - General, 1950 -- 1997; UA018.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
    - Citizens Participation Course Proposal, 1950 -- 1997; UA018.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
    - Health Courses, 1950 -- 1997; UA018.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
    - Urban Social and Environmental Policy (Graduate Program), 1950 -- 1997; UA018.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
    - Citizens Fellowship Program, 1950 -- 1997; UA018.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
    - Engineering Program (Workshop), 1950 -- 1997; UA018.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
    - Environmental Advocacy, 1950 -- 1997; UA018.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
    - Background, 1950 -- 1997; UA018.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
    - Ma. Assembly - State Government, 1959 -- 1960; UA018.001.065.00001 (Box 65)
    - Community Schools, 1970; UA018.001.065.00002 (Box 65)
    - Metropolitan Education Service Center, 1971 -- 1972; UA018.001.065.00003 (Box 65)
    - MACE, 1969 -- 1971; UA018.001.065.00004 (Box 65)
    - Regional Service Center, 1967 -- 1971; UA018.001.065.00005 (Box 65)
    - Student Rights and Responsibilities, 1970 -- 1971; UA018.001.065.00006 (Box 65)
    - Civic Affairs, 1961 -- 1965; UA018.001.065.00007 (Box 65)
    - Law Seminar, 1971 -- 1972; UA018.001.066.00001 (Box 66)
    - Fletcher - AID, 1970; UA018.001.066.00002 (Box 66)
    - Research Papers, 1958 -- 1959; UA018.001.066.00003 (Box 66)
  - Subject files, 1961 -- 1982; UA018.001.002
    - Lincoln Filene Center, 1961; UA018.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
    - Lincoln Filene Center, 1962; UA018.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
    - Lincoln Filene Center, 1963; UA018.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
    - Lincoln Filene Center, 1964; UA018.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
    - Lincoln Filene Center, 1965; UA018.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
    - Lincoln Filene Center, 1966; UA018.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
    - Lincoln Filene Center, 1967; UA018.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
    - Lincoln Filene Center, 1968; UA018.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
    - Lincoln Filene Center, 1969; UA018.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
    - Lincoln Filene Center, 1970; UA018.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
    - Lincoln Filene Center, 1971; UA018.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
    - Lincoln Filene Center, 1972; UA018.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
    - Lincoln Filene Center, 1973; UA018.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
    - Lincoln Filene Center, 1973; UA018.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
    - Lincoln Filene Center Meeting, 1973; UA018.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
    - Lincoln Filene Center, 1974; UA018.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
    - Lincoln Filene Center, 1975; UA018.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
    - Assessment, 1970 -- 1982; UA018.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
    - Biston Associates, 1970; UA018.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
    - Educational Renewal Program, 1904 -- 1972; UA018.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
    - JFK Library, 1971 -- 1972; UA018.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
    - Office of Education, 1973; UA018.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
    - Projections, 1968 -- 1970; UA018.001.004.00008 (Box 4)
    - Tappan, 1965 -- 1972; UA018.001.004.00009 (Box 4)
    - Title I, 1969 -- 1971; UA018.001.004.00010 (Box 4)
    - West Virginia, 1971 -- 1972; UA018.001.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Title III, 1962 -- 1979; UA018.001.003
    - Publicity, 1971 -- 1973; UA018.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
    - AFIRE, 1970 -- 1972; UA018.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
    - Forms, 1970 -- 1972; UA018.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
    - Minutes, Budget, Addendum, Proposal, 1971 -- 1972; UA018.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
    - Minutes, Budget, Proposal, Awards, 1972 -- 1973; UA018.001.005.00005 (Box 5)
      Includes a folder on Medford
    - Proposal, 1965 -- 1972; UA018.001.005.00006 (Box 5)
    - Grant Application, 1972; UA018.001.006.00001 (Box 6)
    - Completed Reports, 1973; UA018.001.006.00002 (Box 6)
    - Proposal (Original Draft), UA018.001.006.00003 (Box 6)
    - Basic Proposal, 1970 -- 1971; UA018.001.006.00004 (Box 6)
    - Second Year Proposal, 1970 -- 1972; UA018.001.006.00005 (Box 6)
    - Third Year Proposal, 1971 -- 1972; UA018.001.006.00006 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1970 -- 1971; UA018.001.006.00007 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1972; UA018.001.006.00008 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1973 -- 1974; UA018.001.007.00001 (Box 7)
    - Memos, 1971 -- 1972; UA018.001.007.00002 (Box 7)
    - Lists, UA018.001.007.00003 (Box 7)
    - Evaluations (1), 1971 -- 1972; UA018.001.007.00004 (Box 7)
    - Evaluations (2), UA018.001.007.00005 (Box 7)
    - Shephard Knapp School, UA018.001.007.00006 (Box 7)
    - Workshops, 1973; UA018.001.007.00007 (Box 7)
    - Feedback, 1971 -- 1972; UA018.001.007.00008 (Box 7)
    - Consultant Visits, 1971 -- 1972; UA018.001.007.00009 (Box 7)
    - On-Site Evaluations, 1972 -- 1973; UA018.001.007.00010 (Box 7)
    - Browne and Nichols, 1974 -- 1975; UA018.001.007.00011 (Box 7)
    - System Share of Costs, 1973; UA018.001.007.00012 (Box 7)
    - Diffusion, 1974; UA018.001.008.00001 (Box 8)
    - Teacher Stipends, 1971; UA018.001.008.00002 (Box 8)
    - "Invent Your Own" Workshop, 1972; UA018.001.008.00003 (Box 8)
    - Multiplier Effect, 1972 -- 1973; UA018.001.008.00004 (Box 8)
    - Curriculum Manuscripts, UA018.001.008.00005 (Box 8)
    - Boston Ballet, 1973 -- 1974; UA018.001.008.00006 (Box 8)
    - Local Support, 1972; UA018.001.008.00007 (Box 8)
    - Local School Committees, 1971 -- 1972; UA018.001.008.00008 (Box 8)
    - PACE, 1971 -- 1972; UA018.001.008.00009 (Box 8)
    - Innovative Schools, 1971 -- 1974; UA018.001.008.00010 (Box 8)
    - Financial Report, 1973 -- 1974; UA018.001.008.00011 (Box 8)
    - Budget, 1971 -- 1973; UA018.001.008.00012 (Box 8)
    - Agreements, 1971 -- 1972; UA018.001.008.00013 (Box 8)
    - Grant and Backup, 1972 -- 1975; UA018.001.009.00001 (Box 9)
    - AFIRE: Kaiser, 1973 -- 1974; UA018.001.009.00002 (Box 9)
    - AFIRE: Grants, 1972 -- 1973; UA018.001.009.00003 (Box 9)
    - Bellingham School Project, 1972 -- 1973; UA018.001.009.00004 (Box 9)
    - Blanchard Foundation, 1972 -- 1973; UA018.001.009.00005 (Box 9)
    - Boston Urban Observatory, 1970 -- 1972; UA018.001.031.00001 (Box 31)
    - Office of Juvenile Delinquency, 1963 -- 1964; UA018.001.031.00002 (Box 31)
    - Office of Juvenile Delinquency, 1964 -- 1965; UA018.001.031.00003 (Box 31)
    - Educational Personnel Development, 1968 -- 1970; UA018.001.031.00004 (Box 31)
    - Institute for Services to Education, 1966; UA018.001.031.00005 (Box 31)
    - Negro - American Proposal, 1962 -- 1964; UA018.001.031.00006 (Box 31)
    - Research Analysis and Allocation, 1968 -- 1970; UA018.001.031.00007 (Box 31)
    - School Board Grant Proposal, 1965; UA018.001.031.00008 (Box 31)
    - State Leadership Conference, 1966; UA018.001.031.00009 (Box 31)
    - STAR Grant Proposal, 1970; UA018.001.031.00010 (Box 31)
    - Pilot Project Proposal, 1973 -- 1979; UA018.001.031.00011 (Box 31)
      Correspondence with New World Foundation
  - New Frontiers - K6, 1960 -- 1970; UA018.001.004
    - NDEA, New Frontiers, 1968; UA018.001.010.00001 (Box 10)
    - Families in Japan: A social study, 1966; UA018.001.010.00002 (Box 10)
    - The Matchbox Project, Publications, 1966; UA018.001.010.00003 (Box 10)
    - Social Concepts: a case study, UA018.001.010.00004 (Box 10)
    - Prentice Hall: Man in Action, 1966; UA018.001.010.00005 (Box 10)
    - Fairfield Public Schools: Experimental Program, 1963; UA018.001.010.00006 (Box 10)
    - Newton Public Schools: The Tokyo Plain, 1964; UA018.001.010.00007 (Box 10)
    - Whitnall Schools: Living Together, 1965; UA018.001.010.00008 (Box 10)
    - Chula Vista Schools: Geography, 1964; UA018.001.011.00001 (Box 11)
    - Tulsa Public Schools: Social Studies, 1964; UA018.001.011.00002 (Box 11)
    - Providence Social Studies, 1964 -- 1965; UA018.001.011.00003 (Box 11)
    - Franklin and Lexington Schools: Social Studies, 1960; UA018.001.011.00004 (Box 11)
    - Tulsa Public Schools: Curriculum Guide, 1964; UA018.001.011.00005 (Box 11)
    - Education Guides, 1965 -- 1970; UA018.001.011.00006 (Box 11)
    - Springboards, Utica Public Schools, 1962 -- 1966; UA018.001.012.00001 (Box 12)
    - St. Paul Public, National Council for the Social Studies, 1966; UA018.001.012.00002 (Box 12)
    - Research and Development in the Social Studies, 1965; UA018.001.012.00003 (Box 12)
      publ. by The Social Studies Curriculum Program Educational Services Incorporated
  - New Frontiers - Subjects, 1950 -- 1968; UA018.001.005
    - History, 1960 -- 1965; UA018.001.012.00004 (Box 12)
      from Brookline, Newton and Utica, NY schools
    - History, 1957 -- 1965; UA018.001.012.00005 (Box 12)
      Publications from many schools and universities on the subject of History in the classroom.
    - History, 1959 -- 1964; UA018.001.013.00001 (Box 13)
      American Historical Association, Utica Public Schools, Social Studies Curriculum Program
    - History, 1963 -- 1967; UA018.001.013.00002 (Box 13)
      Atlantic Information Centre for Teachers, Milwaukee Public Schools, Binghamton NY, etc.
    - Geography, UA018.001.013.00003 (Box 13)
      A sample study, Curriculum Guide supplements, Tulsa Public Schools
    - Geography, 1962 -- 1966; UA018.001.013.00004 (Box 13)
      Teaching Guides
    - Geography, 1960 -- 1963; UA018.001.013.00005 (Box 13)
    - Geography, 1964; UA018.001.014.00001 (Box 14)
      Curriculum Guides
    - Geography, 1961 -- 1964; UA018.001.014.00002 (Box 14)
    - Geography, 1960 -- 1963; UA018.001.014.00003 (Box 14)
    - Political Science, 1959 -- 1966; UA018.001.015.00001 (Box 15)
      Curriculum Guides, Progress Reports, American Political Science Association
    - Political Science, 1962 -- 1966; UA018.001.015.00002 (Box 15)
      Assorted materials
    - Political Science, 1964 -- 1966; UA018.001.015.00003 (Box 15)
      Curriculum Development Center, Congress and the Committee System, Teachers Work Politically
    - Political Science, 1968; UA018.001.015.00004 (Box 15)
      Public Issues Series, Harvard Social Studies Project
    - Political Science, 1965 -- 1967; UA018.001.015.00005 (Box 15)
      Center of Intercultural Documentation; Judgement: Teacher's Guide to Case Study (#'s 1-10)
    - Political Science: Taft Institute, 1967 -- 1968; UA018.001.015.00006 (Box 15)
    - Social Studies, 1964; UA018.001.016.00001 (Box 16)
      Administration; History of Social Studies; News Focus
    - Social Studies, 1962 -- 1966; UA018.001.016.00002 (Box 16)
      State Departments of Education, Asian Studies
    - Social Studies, 1962 -- 1966; UA018.001.016.00003 (Box 16)
      Anthropology, Sociology, Psychology
    - Intergroup Relations, 1965 -- 1966; UA018.001.016.00004 (Box 16)
      Equality of Education
    - Social Studies: History, 1961 -- 1964; UA018.001.017.00001 (Box 17)
    - History, 1960 -- 1964; UA018.001.017.00002 (Box 17)
    - Social Studies, 1961; UA018.001.017.00003 (Box 17)
      Public School Department Guides
    - Social Studies, 1961 -- 1963; UA018.001.017.00004 (Box 17)
      Problems Of Democracy
    - Social Studies, 1960 -- 1965; UA018.001.018.00001 (Box 18)
      Eastern Studies; Curriculum Guides
    - Social Studies, 1963 -- 1967; UA018.001.018.00002 (Box 18)
      Subject Guides: Ethnocentrism, Liberty
    - Anthropology, UA018.001.018.00003 (Box 18)
      Anthropology Study Curriculum Project
    - Education and Race Relations, 1965; UA018.001.018.00004 (Box 18)
      Study Guide and Discussion Outline for "Education and Race Relations"
    - Social Studies, 1965 -- 1967; UA018.001.018.00005 (Box 18)
      Educational Aides
    - Social Studies, 1964; UA018.001.018.00006 (Box 18)
      Curriculum Development Center: Comparative Political Systems
    - Latin American Studies, 1968; UA018.001.019.00001 (Box 19)
      Latin American Curriculum Project
    - Political Science, 1967 -- 1968; UA018.001.019.00002 (Box 19)
      Essays on; Educational Aids
    - Social Studies, 1967 -- 1968; UA018.001.019.00003 (Box 19)
      Teaching Guides, Film Guides
    - Social Studies, 1968; UA018.001.019.00004 (Box 19)
      Curriculum and Subject Guides
    - Social Studies, 1967 -- 1968; UA018.001.019.00005 (Box 19)
      African-American Studies
    - Social Studies, 1967 -- 1968; UA018.001.019.00006 (Box 19)
      Economics, Political Games
    - Social Studies, 1960 -- 1964; UA018.001.019.00007 (Box 19)
      Austin Schools, B'Nai B'rith
    - Social Studies, 1965 -- 1968; UA018.001.019.00008 (Box 19)
      Economics, Social Studies Curriculum Directory
    - Social Studies, 1960; UA018.001.019.00009 (Box 19)
      "Social Studies in the Elementary School Program"
    - Social Studies, 1964 -- 1966; UA018.001.019.00010 (Box 19)
      New York and California and Maine; progress reports
    - Social Studies, 1950 -- 1964; UA018.001.019.00011 (Box 19)
      Planning, Development
  - New Frontiers - Teaching aids, 1961 -- 1968; UA018.001.006
    - Teaching - Learning Process, 1963 -- 1965; UA018.001.020.00001 (Box 20)
    - Teaching - Learning Process, 1963 -- 1965; UA018.001.020.00002 (Box 20)
      Economics Games, Case Studies. Political Case Studies.
    - Teaching - Learning Process, 1963 -- 1966; UA018.001.020.00003 (Box 20)
      Urban Systems Games, Case Studies
    - Teaching Aids, 1964; UA018.001.020.00004 (Box 20)
    - Teaching Aids, 1963 -- 1965; UA018.001.020.00005 (Box 20)
    - Teaching Aids: Anthropology, 1963 -- 1965; UA018.001.020.00006 (Box 20)
    - Teaching Aids: Cartography, UA018.001.020.00007 (Box 20)
    - Teaching Aids: Audio Visual Tools, 1964; UA018.001.020.00008 (Box 20)
    - Case Studies, 1963 -- 1965; UA018.001.021.00001 (Box 21)
    - Mass Media and Communications in Teaching, 1963 -- 1966; UA018.001.021.00002 (Box 21)
    - Programmed Instruction, 1961 -- 1965; UA018.001.021.00003 (Box 21)
    - Social Studies, 1964 -- 1965; UA018.001.021.00004 (Box 21)
    - Social Studies, 1964; UA018.001.021.00005 (Box 21)
    - Teaching Aids, 1964; UA018.001.022.00001 (Box 22)
      Film Use
    - Curriculum, 1964 -- 1966; UA018.001.022.00002 (Box 22)
    - Teacher Preparation, 1963 -- 1966; UA018.001.022.00003 (Box 22)
    - CoCurricula Studies, 1968; UA018.001.022.00004 (Box 22)
  - HEW, 1963 -- 1976; UA018.001.007
    - Boston Problems, 1976; UA018.001.023.00001 (Box 23)
    - Environmental Affairs, 1975 -- 1976; UA018.001.023.00002 (Box 23)
    - Environmental Affairs, 1964 -- 1973; UA018.001.023.00003 (Box 23)
    - Final Report, 1969; UA018.001.023.00004 (Box 23)
      Development of Curriculum in American Civilization for the General Student: Case Study Approach
    - Kenosian Report, 1968 -- 1969; UA018.001.023.00005 (Box 23)
    - President's Commission on Juvenile Delinquency, 1964; UA018.001.023.00006 (Box 23)
    - Massachusetts Department of Education, 1969; UA018.001.023.00007 (Box 23)
    - 404 Proposal, 1972 -- 1973; UA018.001.024.00001 (Box 24)
    - Development of Instructional Materials Relating to Race and Culture, 1966 -- 1967; UA018.001.024.00002 (Box 24)
    - Development of Instructional Materials Pertaining to Race and Culture in American Life, 1966; UA018.001.024.00003 (Box 24)
    - K-6 Project, 1963 -- 1964; UA018.001.024.00004 (Box 24)
    - K-6 Project, 1966 -- 1967; UA018.001.024.00005 (Box 24)
    - K-6 Project, 1967 -- 1969; UA018.001.024.00006 (Box 24)
    - K-6 Project, 1969; UA018.001.024.00007 (Box 24)
    - HEW: Commissioner of Education, 1966; UA018.001.025.00001 (Box 25)
    - HEW: K-6 Proposal, 1964 -- 1966; UA018.001.025.00002 (Box 25)
  - LEA, 1971 -- 1974; UA018.001.008
    - LEAA: Final Report, 1973 -- 1974; UA018.001.025.00003 (Box 25)
    - LEAA: Law Education Proposal, 1971 -- 1974; UA018.001.025.00004 (Box 25)
      incl. Parole Board Game
  - MACE, 1967 -- 1970; UA018.001.009
    - MACE, 1967 -- 1970; UA018.001.025.00005 (Box 25)
      The Massachusetts Department of Education: Operations, Functions and Proposals
    - MACE, 1969 -- 1970; UA018.001.026.00001 (Box 26)
      Massachusetts Advisory Council for Education
  - NDEA, 1965 -- 1969; UA018.001.010
    - NDEA, 1968; UA018.001.026.00002 (Box 26)
    - NDEA, 1968 -- 1969; UA018.001.026.00003 (Box 26)
    - NDEA, 1967; UA018.001.026.00004 (Box 26)
    - NDEA Institute, 1967; UA018.001.026.00005 (Box 26)
    - NDEA Workshop, 1966; UA018.001.027.00001 (Box 27)
    - NDEA Workshop, 1967; UA018.001.027.00002 (Box 27)
    - NDEA: UCLA, 1965 -- 1967; UA018.001.027.00003 (Box 27)
    - NDEA: Proposal for Advanced Study, 1966 -- 1967; UA018.001.027.00004 (Box 27)
    - NDEA: Disadvantaged Youth, 1965; UA018.001.028.00001 (Box 28)
    - NDEA: Disadvantaged Youth, 1966 -- 1967; UA018.001.028.00002 (Box 28)
    - NDEA: Disadvantaged Youth, 1965; UA018.001.028.00003 (Box 28)
    - NDEA: Disadvantaged Youth, 1965 -- 1966; UA018.001.028.00004 (Box 28)
  - NSF, 1967 -- 1976; UA018.001.011
    - NSF, 1967 -- 1970; UA018.001.028.00005 (Box 28)
      National Science Foundation
    - NSF: Survey, 1974 -- 1976; UA018.001.028.00006 (Box 28)
    - NSF: Political Science Institute, 1972 -- 1975; UA018.001.028.00007 (Box 28)
    - NSF: Summer Institute, 1973; UA018.001.029.00001 (Box 29)
      Economics, Political Science
    - NSF: Economics, 1972; UA018.001.029.00002 (Box 29)
    - NSF: Population Growth and Control, 1972; UA018.001.029.00003 (Box 29)
    - NSF: Proposal, 1972; UA018.001.029.00004 (Box 29)
    - NSF, 1967; UA018.001.029.00005 (Box 29)
    - NSF, 1968; UA018.001.029.00006 (Box 29)
    - NSF, 1968; UA018.001.029.00007 (Box 29)
  - Title I, 1965 -- 1975; UA018.001.012
    - Title I: Proposal, 1969; UA018.001.029.00008 (Box 29)
    - Title I: Health Care Accessibility, 1973 -- 1975; UA018.001.029.00009 (Box 29)
      Chinese Community
  - Project IMPACT, 1965 -- 1976; UA018.001.013
    - Memos, 1974 -- 1976; UA018.001.030.00001 (Box 30)
    - Budget Material, 1974 -- 1975; UA018.001.030.00002 (Box 30)
    - Minutes, 1973 -- 1975; UA018.001.030.00003 (Box 30)
    - I/E Survey, 1975; UA018.001.030.00004 (Box 30)
    - Proposals, 1972 -- 1975; UA018.001.030.00005 (Box 30)
    - Reports / Proposals, 1972 -- 1975; UA018.001.030.00006 (Box 30)
    - Dental Project, 1974; UA018.001.030.00007 (Box 30)
    - Health Education Analysis, 1974 -- 1975; UA018.001.030.00008 (Box 30)
    - Press Releases, 1973; UA018.001.030.00009 (Box 30)
      Sampan
    - Council Report, 1973 -- 1974; UA018.001.030.00010 (Box 30)
    - A/V Materials, 1974; UA018.001.030.00011 (Box 30)
    - Report To Executive Board, 1973 -- 1974; UA018.001.030.00012 (Box 30)
    - Legal Descriptions, 1965; UA018.001.030.00013 (Box 30)
  - Grant Proposals, 1972 -- 1978; UA018.001.014
    - Economics and Politics of Urban Transportation, 1976; UA018.001.032.00001 (Box 32)
    - Postsecondary Education Program, 1974 -- 1978; UA018.001.032.00002 (Box 32)
    - State Formulae for Local Government Revenue Sharing, 1975; UA018.001.032.00003 (Box 32)
    - Prospectus: Relationship of Personal Education of Transportation Costs, 1973; UA018.001.032.00004 (Box 32)
    - NSF Grant, 1972; UA018.001.032.00005 (Box 32)
  - Past Programs, 1959 -- 1975; UA018.001.015
    - Age Center Project, 1960 -- 1961; UA018.001.033.00001 (Box 33)
    - American Heritage, 1963 -- 1965; UA018.001.033.00002 (Box 33)
    - American Heritage, 1963 -- 1965; UA018.001.033.00003 (Box 33)
    - Awards, 1960 -- 1965; UA018.001.033.00004 (Box 33)
    - Basic Tasks and Public Leadership, 1959 -- 1962; UA018.001.033.00005 (Box 33)
    - Basic Issues, 1964; UA018.001.033.00006 (Box 33)
    - Basic Issues, 1965; UA018.001.033.00007 (Box 33)
    - Boston Public Schools, 1967 -- 1969; UA018.001.033.00008 (Box 33)
    - Boston State College, 1969; UA018.001.033.00009 (Box 33)
    - Brockton Public Schools, 1971; UA018.001.033.00010 (Box 33)
    - Cambridge In - Service, 1968; UA018.001.033.00011 (Box 33)
    - Civic Education Seminar, 1974; UA018.001.034.00001 (Box 34)
    - Civic Education and Development, 1970; UA018.001.034.00002 (Box 34)
    - Civic Education Conference, 1967; UA018.001.034.00003 (Box 34)
    - Colorado, 1970; UA018.001.034.00004 (Box 34)
    - CONE, 1965; UA018.001.034.00005 (Box 34)